That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Gabiru Is Here!
It's been a few days since Benimaru
and his comrades joined us.
（リムル）
ベニマルたちが
仲間になって
数日が過ぎた
（ガルム）ふへえ〜
This stuff sure is nice.
（ガルム）きれいなもんだなあ
So this is silk cloth, Shuna?
（ドルド）
これが絹糸で織った反物
ってやつかい？　シュナちゃん
（シュナ）はい
Yes, the Hellmoth cocoons it's
made from are full of magicules,
原料のヘルモスの繭には
魔素(まそ)が たっぷり含まれているので
so it's very sturdy.
とても丈夫なのですよ
I see.
（ガルム）
なるほど…
防御力も期待できるってことかい
So it should give us some good protection.
That's amazing!
（リムル）すごいな
You can already weave silk?
（リムル）
もう絹織物なんて出来たのか
Great Rimuru!
（シュナ）リムル様！
Hiya.
（ガルム）ども
（ドルド）こんにちは
Hey there.
He still won't talk!
（リムル）
やっぱ しゃべらねえ！
You came to see us, Great Rimuru!
（シュナ）
いらしてくださったんですね
リムル様
Y-Yeah. How're things going?
（リムル）
うっ うむ… どんな具合だ？
Great. The weaving loom Sir Kaijin
made for me is very easy to use.
（シュナ）
はい カイジン様が
作ってくださった織機は
とても使いやすいです
Yeah? Glad to hear it.
（リムル）そうか よかった
I'm counting on you to
make clothes for everyone.
みんなの衣類の製作 頼んだぞ
はい！　お任せください
Of course! Leave it to me!
（シオン）
では リムル様 参りましょう
Now then, let us go, Great Rimuru.
お昼が冷めてしまいます
Our lunch will get cold.
（シュナ）あっ シオン
Shion...
秘書のお仕事は
ちゃんとできているのですか？
Is your secretarial work going well?
もちろんです シュナ様
Of course, Princess Shuna.
Shion declared herself my secretary.
（リムル）
シオンは 俺の秘書を名乗り出た
She kinda looks like one, so I accepted.
見た目もそれっぽいので承諾した
Now, she's both my secretary
and my bodyguard.
今は秘書 兼 俺の護衛役だ
（シュナ）ウフフ…
私がリムル様のお世話をしても
いいのですよ？
I wouldn't mind taking care
of Great Rimuru myself.
いいえ 姫
それには及びません
Oh, no, Princess. There's no need for that.
私が きちんとお世話いたします
I will take good care of him.
These two seem to have a rivalry going on...
（リムル）
なんか この２人 張り合うんだよな
I think I'll take care of
Great Rimuru, after all.
（シュナ）
やはり リムル様は
私が お世話いたします
No, as his secretary, I'll do that.
（シオン）いいえ 秘書である私が
リムル様は 私とシオン
Great Rimuru, would you prefer
to have me or Shion serving you?
どちらが おそばに仕えたほうが
よいと思われますか？
W-Well... You need to be weaving silk, right?
（リムル）そ… そうだね
シュナは
絹織りという仕事があるだろ？
Maybe I'll have you help
out in your spare time...
手の空いたときにでも頼もうかな
What the heck am I asking for?!
（リムル）
一体 俺は何を頼むのか！
分かりました
Very well!
私は頼られているのですね！
You're asking for my help, then?
E-Exactly! I'm counting on you!
（リムル）
そ… そのとおりだ　頼むぞ
Seriously, what the heck am I asking for?!
（リムル）
一体 俺は何を頼んでいるのか！
Well, then, please leave Great Rimuru to me.
それでは リムル様のこと
お任せください
Oh, hello, Great Rimuru.
（ベニマル）
ああ… これは リムル様
Have you come to eat?
（ハクロウ）お食事ですかな？
Yeah. Shion said she cooked me a meal.
（リムル）
ああ シオンが手料理を
作ってくれたって言うのでな
Want to join me, guys?
（リムル）
お前たちも 一緒にどうだ？
Oh, I'm not really hungry...
いや… 俺は 今は腹が減ってなくて
Yes, we'll just have tea.
（ハクロウ）ええ お茶だけで
I will...
（ソウエイ）私は…
Oh, he can use the Body Double skill now?
（リムル）
おっ！　分身のスキルまで
使えるようになってたのか
...go out and scout the surrounding area!
（ソウエイたち）
村の周囲の偵察に行ってまいります
では お持ちしますね
I'll bring it out, then.
Oh... Sure.
I wonder why the guys reacted that way...
（リムル）
なんか
ベニマルたちの反応が気になる
Is it because, even though
Shion looks really capable,
シオン…
そんな できる女みたいな外見して
まさか！
it's going to end up being that old trope?
そんな お約束みたいな
アレだったりする… のか？
I've returned!
お待たせしました
Please, help yourself.
さっ 召し上がれ
She's not capable at all!
（リムル）
ダメだった！
"Not hungry," my ass!
（リムル）
なにが腹いっぱいだ
They ran away because they
knew she couldn't cook!
シオンがメシマズだと知ってて
逃げやがったな
Great Rimuru, help yourself.
（シオン）リムル様 さっ どうぞ
Hey, you! Look at me!
（リムル）
おい こら！　こっち向け
How dare you just casually sip that tea?!
なに普通に 茶すすってんだ！
And the old geezer's totally
erased his presence!
ていうか じいさん
完全に気配を断(た)ってやがる
Hey!
お〜い！
Go on, Great Rimuru.
（シオン）ささ リムル様
Forgive me, Great Rimuru.
（ベニマル）すまない リムル様
（ハクロウ）これも修業ですじゃ
Consider this training.
Whew, I'm starved!
（ゴブタ）腹 減ったっす〜
Please, before it gets cold.
（シオン）ささ 冷めないうちに
H-Here I go, then.
い… いただきます
はい
Yes!
Well, hey, it's not like it's poison.
（リムル）
な〜に さすがに毒ではあるまい
I won't die or—
死ぬことはな…
う… 落ち着け
Okay, relax. It looks like it's possessed,
but it's just my imagination!
何か取りついているように
見えるが… 気のせいだ
Right, it's just... that!
そう これは… あれだ
A simulacrum.
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
シミュラクラ現象
Simulacrum
The tendency to see a face
in anything with three distinctly
visible points.
The tendency to see a face in anything
with three distinctly visible points.
Uh, I don't need that explanation right now.
（リムル）
いや 今 そんな説明いいから
Guoooogh
Help me, Great Sage!
助けて 大賢者！
Answer.
（大賢者）
解(かい)…
If you close your eyes and insert the spoon
at an angle from the right, you will not die.
視覚を閉ざし
右斜め後方にスプーンを突き出せば
命は助かります
Guoooogh
I don't really get it, but okay!
よく分からんけど 分かった！
Mrgh!
（ゴブタ）むぐ！
"Mrgh"?
むぐ？
（ゴブタ）うっ！　うぐ…
ぐわあああ！
おわっ！
あれ？
Oh, dear.
（リムル）シオン
（シオン）は… はい！
Shion...
Y-Yes?!
Next time you make food
to serve to someone else,
今後 人に出す飲食物を作るときは
get Benimaru's approval first.
ベニマルの許可を得てから
するように
That's just cruel, Great Rimuru!
（ベニマル）
あんまりです リムル様
Don't blame me. You're her supervisor now.
（リムル）
知らん　監督は お前に任せた
I need Benimaru to do a good job
ベニマルには頑張ってもらいたい
so we don't suffer any
more losses like Gobta.
今後 二度と
ゴブタのような犠牲を出さぬために
Gabiru the Lizardman continued
to earn the cooperation
（リムル）
リザードマンのガビルは
近隣のゴブリンの村々から
of other nearby Goblin villages.
順調に協力を取り付けていた
Granted, it wasn't so
much Gabiru's persuasion
もっとも ガビルの力というよりは
オークの侵略におびえる
ゴブリンたちが
as it was the Goblins willingly
capitulating in fear of the Orc invasion.
勝手に軍門に下っていってるだけ
なのであるが
（部下Ａ）う〜む…
This gives us a total of 7,000 Goblins.
これで総勢7000匹になりましたな
Way to go, Sir Gabiru!
You're a great negotiator!
（部下Ｂ）
さっすが ガビル様！　交渉も上手
Not at all.
It just so happens my best
efforts are being rewarded.
精いっぱいやって
たまたま結果が出ているだけのこと
Don't be so humble! It's pure talent!
（部下Ｃ）謙遜すんなよ 実力だよ
Yeah! Be more confident in yourself!
（部下Ｂ）
そうですよ
もっと自信を持ってくださいよ
Indeed.
（部下Ａ）しかり
You will be the Lizardman
chieftain one day, after all.
次期リザードマンの首領
なのだからな
R-Right...
（ガビル）そ… そうか？
Maybe... I really am pretty great!
（ガビル）
やっぱり 我が輩…
イケてるのかもしれん！
あ〜 それで
次は どこに向かうのだ
So, where are we headed next?
Are there any more villages around here?
この辺りに ほかに村はあるのか？
It seems there is one more settlement.
（部下Ｂ）
もう１つ 集落があるって話ですよ
But the residents of the previous
village had odd things to say about it.
（部下Ａ）
しかし… 先ほどの村の者が
おかしなことを言っておった
Odd things?
（ガビル）おかしなこと？
They said it was a settlement of
Goblins that have tamed Direwolves.
なんでも
牙狼族(がろうぞく)を操るゴブリンの集落だとか
What? Goblins and Direwolves?
はあ？　ゴブリンが牙狼を？
そんなわけないだろう
That's impossible.
I agree.
ごもっとも
更に言えば
そのゴブリンたちの親玉
What's more, they said the leader
of these Goblins is a slime.
スライムだという
What?!
状況が よく分からぬが…
I don't quite understand that scenario...
But if that's the case,
then if that slime works for us,
ならば そのスライムを
支配下に置けば
we'll be able to control the Direwolves, too!
牙狼族をも支配できる
ということだな！
Oh!
一石二鳥！
Two birds with one stone!
なんて奥深い考えだ！
What profound thinking!
やはり
あんたに ついてきてよかったぜ！
I'm glad I came along with you!
Just leave everything to me!
我が輩に任せておくがいい！
Yeah, Sir Gabiru! Say it!
（部下Ｂ）いよっ！　ガビル様！
Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru!
（部下Ｂ）あっ そ〜れ ガビル♪
（ガビル）フフフフ…
（部下たち）ガビル！
（ガビル）フフフフフ…
（部下たち）ガビル！　ガビル！
（ガビル）ヌア〜ッハッハッハ！
Really? You just decide the best heat
level for tempering by instinct?
（カイジン）
へえ〜 焼き入れんときの温度
勘なのかい？
Sure do. I can tell from
the color of the flame.
（クロベエ）
んだ
火の色を見れば 大体 分かるだよ
（カイジン）俺は 測るなあ
I always measure it...
I measure it the second time around, too.
（クロベエ）
おらも 戻しのときは
きちっと測るだよ
Right, if the outside's cold,
it won't be pliable.
（カイジン）
ああ
外が寒いと粘りが出ねえからな
Do you measure the amount of dirt
you use when tempering, too?
Kurobe and Kaijin hit it off immediately.
（リムル）
クロベエは すっかり
カイジンと意気投合したようで
Right, you gotta watch the amount, but the
quality of the dirt is important, too.
They've been talking about this
technical stuff for two hours now.
かれこれ２時間
専門的な会話が続いている
Oh, I can tell you what the best dirt is.
（クロベエ）
あっ それだったら
オラが いい土を教えてやるだ
That'd be great!
I came to check in on them, but I couldn't
find the right moment to excuse myself,
（リムル）
様子を見に来た俺は うっかり
中座するタイミングを逃して
Different dirt completely
changes the finished product!
so here I am.
今に至る
Right?
（カイジン）な？
（クロベエ）鍛造(たんぞう)って面白いべ？
Isn't forging fascinating?
Y-Yeah...
（リムル）お… おう
So about the water you use when tempering...
（クロベエ）
あっ 焼き入れのときの
水加減だけんど…
Is Great Rimuru in here?
（リグルド）
リムル様は
いらっしゃいますかな？
Nice timing!
（リムル）
ナイス タイミング！
What's up, Rigurd?
（リムル）なんだ？　リグルド
リムル様 リザードマンの使者が
訪ねてきました
Great Rimuru, an envoy of
the Lizardmen has arrived.
Great Rimuru.
（ベニマル）リムル様
俺たちも同席して かまわないか？
Would you mind if we accompanied you?
リザードマンの思惑が知りたい
We want to know what the Lizardmen are up to.
Of course.
（リムル）もちろんだ
Now, then...
さて…
Are we dealing with friend or foe here?
果たして 敵か 味方か
Which one's the envoy?
（リムル）どいつが使者だ？
That's a rather dramatic entry...
（リムル）
随分 芝居がかった登場だな
（地面を突く音 止まる）
Hup!
とう！
I am Gabiru of the Lizardmen.
我が輩は リザードマンの
ガビルである
お前らも配下に加えてやろう
You will all serve under me.
Consider this a great honor!
光栄に思うがよい！
Yeah, Sir Gabiru!
（拍手）
（部下）よっ！　ガビル様
You're the best!
（部下たち）最高！　かっこいい！
So cool!
You're on fire!
イカしてる！
Huh?
Remember him well.
ご尊顔(そんがん)を
よ〜く覚えておくがよいぞ
This is the man who will be the
next chieftain of the Lizardmen!
このお方こそ 次の
リザードマンの首領となられる戦士
Bow down!
頭(ず)が高い！
Huh?
"You will serve under me"?
（リムル）
配下に加えてやる？
光栄に思え？
"Consider it an honor"?
Bigshot! Who does he think he is?
偉そうに… 一体 何様のつもりだ？
って…
And...
Shion-san, please stop!
（リムル）
ちょ… シオンさん やめて！
You're gonna make this slime way too slim!
スライムボディーが
スリムボディーになっちゃう〜！
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
（シオン）
すみません すみません
すみません！
ゴホン…
Ahem.
Forgive me... You called
yourself Gabiru, yes?
恐れながら
ガビル殿と申されましたかな
This request to serve you is rather sudden...
“配下になれ”と
突然 申されましても…
Good grief. Must I spell it out for you?
やれやれ…
皆まで言わねば分からんか
貴様らも聞いておるだろう
You've heard the news, have you not?
（リグルド）何を…
What news?
The news that those Orc pigs are
invading the Great Forest of Jura.
（ガビル）オークの豚どもが
このジュラの大森林を
侵攻中だという話だ
Oh?
（リムル）
ほほう…
Which is why it would best
suit you to become my men.
しからば 我が輩の
配下に加わるがよい
I, Gabiru, will protect you weaklings
from the threat of the Orcs!
このガビルが 貧弱なお前たちを
オークの脅威より
守ってやろうではないか！
Weaklings!
貧弱な…
Weaklings...
貧弱…
Weaklings?
Wow...
ワ〜オ
ゴブリンがいないようだが
I don't see any Goblins.
What?
あれ〜？
ここは 確かに
ゴブリンの村のはず…
This was supposed to be a Goblin village.
ていうか
貧弱なヤツが誰もいないよ
In fact, I don't see anyone
weak around here...
Well, if Orcs are invading,
（リムル）
まあ オークが攻めてくるのなら
I guess forming a united front
with the Lizardmen is one option...
リザードマンとの共闘ってのも
選択肢のひとつではあるんだが
But I'm not sure I want him watching my back.
あいつに背中を預けるのは
ちょっと嫌だな
He seems pretty stupid.
アホそうだし
"What one should really fear is not a
competent enemy, but an incompetent ally."
“真に恐れるべきは
有能な敵ではなく”
“無能な味方である”って
Didn't Napoleon say that?
ナポレオンの言葉だったっけ？
Ahem!
ゴホン！
聞けば ここには 牙狼族を
飼い慣らした者がいるそうだな
I've heard that there are those
among you who have tamed Direwolves.
そいつは幹部に引き立ててやる
I will make those of you who
have officers in my army.
連れてくるがいいぞ
Bring them to me.
Uh-oh... Shion's getting pissed again!
（リムル）
いかん…
シオンが またイラつき始めた
Can I kill him?
（ベニマル）
こいつ… 殺していいですか？
Sure!
（リムル）
いいよ
Wait, no! No! No!
って ノー！　ノー ノー！
Um... We didn't exactly tame the Direwolves.
（リムル）えっと…
牙狼族を飼い慣らしたというか
We made them our allies,
and I'm the one who did that.
仲間にしたのは俺なんですけど…
スライムが？
A slime did that?
Please don't make such jokes.
冗談を言うでない
Ranga.
（リムル）ランガ
（ランガ）はっ ここに！
Yes, master!
He says he wants to talk
to you. Hear him out.
（リムル）
お前に話があるそうだ
聞いてさしあげろ
As you wish.
（ランガ）御意
— Menace —
ふん！
Wait, was he always that big?
（ベニマル）
あれ？
あんなにデカかったですかね
That's his true size.
（リムル）
あれが本当の大きさなんだよ
This size works better for
intimidating people, you know?
まあ 威嚇するには
あのサイズのほうが都合がいい
My master has ordered me to
hear what you have to say.
（ランガ）主(あるじ)より
お前の相手をする命(めい)を受けた
聞いてやるから 話すがいい
So speak. I'm listening.
貴殿が牙狼族の族長殿かな？
Are you the leader of the Direwolves?
Wow... The other guys are cowering in fear,
へえ〜
ほかのヤツらは萎縮してるけど
あいつ 結構 根性はありそうだな
but this guy seems to have some guts.
Still seems stupid, though.
アホそうだけど
Your beautiful fur, your keen eyes...
美しい毛並み 鋭い眼光
さすが威風堂々たる たたずまい
You truly have a majestic presence.
しかし…
However...
It is a bit disappointing to know
that your master is a slime!
主がスライムとは
いささか拍子抜けであるな
What?!
（リムル）
ああん？
どうやら貴殿は
だまされておるようだ
It seems you've been deceived.
Very well. What this slime has
done to you is unforgivable...
よかろう
この我が輩が貴殿を操る不埒者(ふらちもの)を
so I shall defeat him for you!
倒してみせようではないか！
Sir Gabiru, you're awesome!
ガビル様 かっけ〜！
Show 'em what you're made of, Sir Gabiru!
見せてやってくださいよ
ガビル様！
The peerless Gabiru!
ガビル無双を！
あっ それ♪
Say it!
Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru!
（部下たち）ガビル！　ガビル！
（ガビル）はい！　はい！
（部下たち）ガビル！
（ガビル）あ〜い！
Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru!
A mere lizard dares to insult my master?!
トカゲ風情が…
我が主を愚弄するとは
Uh-oh.
（リムル）
あっ ヤバい
He's dead.
あいつ 死んだ
（ゴブタ）
テ〜ン テッテッ テ〜ン♪
Hey, what're you guys doing?
おっ… 何やってるっすか？
Gobta!
（ベニマル）ゴブタ！
You're still alive?
（リムル）お前 生きてたのか？
Hey, that's kinda mean.
またまた ひどいっす
Of course I'm alive!
ちゃんと生きてるっすよ
Notice.
（大賢者）
告 個体名シオンの
料理に抵抗して
It appears that, in order to
counteract Shion's cooking,
Poison Resistance
he has gained the Poison Resistance skill.
〝毒耐性〞を
獲得したようです
Oh...
（リムル）あっ そう…
Even I don't have Poison
Resistance. I'm impressed.
“毒耐性”って俺も持ってないのに
すごいな
Really?
そうっすか？　エッヘヘヘ
Good timing.
（ランガ）いいところへ来たな
Huh?
なんすか この状況！
What the heck is going on?!
Lizard, if you can defeat this one,
（ランガ）トカゲ
この者を倒せたのなら
貴様の話 一考してやろう
I will consider your offer.
Why me?!
な… なんで？
Wow, Ranga! He's being so calm about this!
（リムル）
お〜 ランガ 意外と冷静だな
Yeah, of course.
If you fought him, you'd kill him.
うんうん
お前じゃ殺しちゃうからな
Fine by me.
（ガビル）かまいませんぞ
Having one of your subordinates
fight saves you the shame of losing.
部下にやらせれば
恥は かきませんからな
フッ… なあ？　スライム殿
Wouldn't you agree, slime?
Gobta, don't hold back! Get him!
（リムル）
ゴブタ 遠慮はいらん　やったれ！
Jeez, why the heck am I doing this?
ええ？　なんなんすか もう…
If you win, I'll have Kurobe make
a special weapon just for you!
（リムル）
勝ったら クロベエに頼んで
お前専用の武器を作ってやる
Really? That motivates me a little!
あっ ホントっすか？
ちょっと やる気 出たっす
And if you lose, you have
to eat Shion's cooking!
（リムル）
負けたら“シオンの手料理の刑”な
Anything but that!
（ゴブタ）それだけは勘弁っす！
For some reason, this conversation
makes me very unhappy.
何やら非常に不愉快な会話です
（リムル）ぐえ！
ふ〜ん！
（部下たち）ガビル様〜！
Sir Gabiru!
準備はいいかな？
Are you ready?
Then begin!
では 始めろ！
Gabiru! Gabiru! Gabiru!
We Lizardman, descendants
of the great Dragons,
偉大なるドラゴンの末裔(まつえい)たる
我らリザードマンが
could never lose to a mere Hobgoblin...
ホブゴブリンなんぞに…
ぬお！
How dare you?!
おのれ こしゃくな！
Impossible! He disappe—
バカな 消え…
I can't believe what I'm seeing!
（リムル）まさか ゴブタのヤツ
Is Gobta actually using Shadow Movement?
“影移動”を使いこなしてんの？
ハア…
終わりだな
That's that.
The fight is over! The winner is Gobta!
勝負あり！　勝者 ゴブタ！
（ベニマル）おっしゃ！
（リグルド）よ〜し！
Yes!
Well done!
All right!
（シオン）やった！
オホホ！
Bravo! Bravo!
（リグルド）わっしょい！
（ゴブタ）アハハハ！
（ゴブタ）高いっす！
This is pretty high!
Nice work, Gobta.
I knew I saw promise in you.
（ランガ）
さすがはゴブタ
我が見込んだだけのことはある
Well done showing them
what a Hobgoblin can do!
（リグルド）
ようやった！
ホブゴブリンの力を
よくぞ見せつけた！
I misjudged you.
（シオン）
見直したぞ
I'll pretend I didn't hear that rude
comment you made about me earlier.
私に対する先ほどの失礼な発言は
聞かなかったことにしてやろう
Looks like he's gotten
stronger since he fought us.
（ベニマル）
俺たちと戦ったときより
強くなっているようだな
It appears he has talent that
would be worth nurturing.
（ハクロウ）
鍛えがいのありそうな才能を
持っているようですじゃ
Is he actually some sort of prodigy?
（リムル）
あいつ
もしかして本当に天才なんじゃ…
Also, did everyone just naturally
believe Gobta would win?
ていうか みんな 普通に
ゴブタが勝つって思ってたの？
てっきり…
I thought...
ぐえ〜！
You will regret...
よくも うちの者(もん)に…
...injuring one of ours!
（リグルド）ケガさしてくれたな
You made the first move, didn't you?
先に手ぇ出したのは そっちでしょ
...they'd pick a fight over it and end
up beating the snot out of that guy.
（リムル）
とか いちゃもんつけて
ボッコボコにするつもりかと
思ってた
It's okay. I'm a guy who
can pick up on the mood.
（リムル）
大丈夫 俺は空気の読める男だ
I'll pretend I expected this to happen.
期待どおりだったことにしよう
Good job, Gobta.
（リムル）やったな ゴブタ！
As promised, I'll have
Kurobe make you a weapon.
約束どおり
クロベエに武器を頼んでやる
All right!
（ゴブタ）やったっす〜！
As for all of you, Gobta has won this battle!
（リムル）
お前ら 勝負はゴブタの勝ちだ
If you want us to help you fight
the Orcs, we'll consider it,
（リムル）
オークと戦うのに協力しろ
という話なら検討しておくが
but we won't serve you.
配下になるのは断る
Take him and leave for today.
今日のところは
そいつを連れて帰れ！
W-We'll be back!
い… いずれ また来るぜ
しかり　これで終わりではないぞ
Indeed. This is not over!
We...
We'll remember this!
覚えてろ〜！
Okay, then...
（リムル）さてと…
I guess we'll have to plan
where to go from here.
今後の方針を立てないとな
I saw 200,000 Orcs.
（ソウエイ）
20万のオーク…
その本体が
大河に沿って北上している
The main army is moving
north along the river.
Based on the movements of this
army and a detached force,
そして 本体と別働隊(べつどうたい)の動きから
予想できる合流地点は
I expect they will regroup in
the marshlands east of here.
ここより東の湿地帯
In the Lizardmen's territory, you mean?
（リグルド）
つまり リザードマンの支配領域
ということですな
（ソウエイ）うむ
20万か…
Two hundred thousand, huh?
That's such a huge number,
it's hard to even imagine it.
実感が湧かないほどバカげた数だな
Just what is it the Orcs are after?
オークの目的って何なんだろうな
ふむ…
オークは そもそも
あまり知能の高い魔物じゃねえ
Orcs are not very intelligent monsters.
If there's something behind this
invasion other than just instinct,
この侵攻に
本能以外の目的があるってんなら
we should suspect there's
someone backing them.
何かしらバックの存在を
疑うべきだろうな
バックの存在だべか？
Someone backing them?
Like a Demon Lord, perhaps?
例えば 魔王とかか？
If that Gelmud guy who came to your
village is involved in this...
お前たちの村に来たという
ゲルミュッドとかいう魔族が
絡んでるんだとしたら…
Well, there's no proof to
base that on right now.
まっ 今のところ何の根拠もないが
And even if it is a Demon Lord, it might
not be the one that made Shizu-san suffer.
（リムル）
魔王だとしても
そいつがシズさんを苦しめた
レオンだとは限らないしな
魔王が絡んでいるかどうかは
分からん
I don't know if a Demon
Lord is involved, but...
（ベニマル）だが…
（リムル）だが？
But?
オークロードが出現した可能性は
強まったと思う
I think this makes it much more likely
that an Orc Lord has appeared.
The unique monster that only
appears once every few centuries?
（リムル）
数百年に一度 生まれる
ユニークモンスターだっけ？
Yes.
（ベニマル）
はい
I can't imagine an ordinary Orc
leading an army of 200,000.
20万もの軍勢を 普通のオークが
統率できるとは思えませんから
（リムル）ふむ…
（ルグルド）
いないと楽観視するよりは
I believe caution would be wiser
than optimism in this case.
警戒するべきかと思います
I agree.
（リムル）そうだな
（リムル）どうした？
What is it?
One of the body doubles I had scouting
the area has made an encounter.
（ソウエイ）
偵察中の分身体に
接触してきた者がいます
An encounter?
（リムル）接触？
They request an audience with you.
（ソウエイ）
リムル様に取り次いでもらいたい
とのこと
How shall I respond?
いかがいたしましょう？
Who is it?
（リムル）
誰だ？
ガビルで もう おなかいっぱいだし
I already had my fill of Gabiru,
so I'd rather not meet anyone weird.
変なヤツだったら
会いたくないんだけど…
I don't believe this one is... weird...
（ソウエイ）
変… ではありませんが
But it is a highly unusual encounter.
大変 珍しい相手でして その…
It's... a Dryad.
ドライアドなのです
A Dryad?!
ドライアド？
Aren't those the girls you see in a lot
of games who are, like, tree spirits?
（リムル）
あれか？　ゲームによくいる
木の精的なおねえちゃんか？
（リグルド）
ドライアド様が
最後に姿を見せたのは
Hasn't it been several decades since
the last time a Dryad showed itself?
数十年以上前ではなかったか？
（リムル）
か… かまわん お呼びして
F-Fine! Bring her here!
Sir.
Ruler of monsters, and all
those who are loyal to him,
（トレイニー）
魔物を統べる者
および その従者たる皆様
forgive me for this unannounced visit.
突然の訪問 相すみません
（トレイニー）
私は
ドライアドのトレイニーと申します
I am Treyni, a Dryad.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
どうぞ お見知りおきください
Dryad  Treyni
I'm Rimuru Tempest... um, Treyni-san.
俺は リムル＝テンペストです
えっと… トレイニーさん
一体 何のご用向きで…
So what brings you here?
I have come to request a favor.
（トレイニー）
本日は お願いがあって
まかり越しました
（リムル）お願い？
A favor?
リムル＝テンペスト
魔物を統べる者よ
Rimuru Tempest, ruler of
monsters, I would like you
あなたに…
to defeat the Orc Lord.
オークロードの討伐を
依頼したいのです
The Gears Spin Out of Control
Next time, "The Gears Spin Out of Control."
（大賢者）
次回「狂いゆく歯車」